Aondohemba Emmanuel

emmyaondohemba45@gmail.com

+2347039575074

Professional Profile

Am a solution. A proactive problem-solver who consistently seeks out challenges and provides innovative solutions. With a keen eye for detail and a deep understanding of user experiences. I tackle problems head-on, delivering elegant solutions. From responsive designs to optimizing performance, I strive to create intuitive and engaging software solutions that leave a lasting impression.

Certifications

- B.Sc. Computer Science
- Google Developers Students Club Lead

Relevant Experience

- Led a cross-functional team of 10 members to successfully deliver a complex software project within the specified timeline and budget.
- Developed and executed project plans, including defining project scope, creating work breakdown structures, and allocating resources effectively.
- Implemented project management methodologies such as Agile or Scrum, resulting in improved team collaboration and increased productivity.
- Managed project risks by identifying and mitigating potential issues, leading to on-time project delivery with minimal disruptions.
- Managed and resolved customer complaints, aiming for a positive resolution while ensuring customer retention and loyalty.
- Collaborated with internal teams to communicate customer feedback and contribute to product improvement initiatives.

Projects/Clients

- DirectEd (app.directed.dev)
- Mintadel
- Acme
- Whodesell whodeysell.com.ng)
- Artboardz (artboardz.net)
- MyCBT (playstore)
- HopSender

Skills

Python, Java, JavaScript, C++, Docker, ReactJs, Next.JS, TypeScript, React-Native, NodeJS User Experience (UX), Rest APIs, AWS, MongoDB, Git, MySQL, Redux, Haskell

Experience

DirectEd. — UK (Remote)

November 2022 - Present

Software Engineer/Smart Contract Integration

• Implement modern frontend framework (NextJs with Typescript) to enhance user experience and improve application performance.e

- Collaborated closely with UI/UX designers and backend developers to ensure seamless integration and consistent design across platforms.
- Integrate Walletconnect using NextJs, mesh, and Cardano Network
- Integrate milestone based smart contract using lucid and Typescript
- Assist with maintenance and upkeep of frontend application.
- Build APIs for interactions with external services and smart contract.
- Use Python and Swagger UI to improve backend codebase.
- Design, implement and test software solutions and integrate with internal and external services.

Artboardz. — UK (Remote)

September 2022 - April 2023

Backend Developer/Smart Contract

- Developed and maintained the infrastructure and Plutus Smart Contract
- Implemented secure user authentication and authorization systems, protecting sensitive customer information.
- Implement offchain code using lucid, NextJs and mesh
- Integrate milestone based smart contract using lucid and Typescript
- Collaborated with frontend developers to implement responsive web designs and ensure consistent user experiences across devices.

Volunteer — (Gimbalabs/IOG)

August 2022 - Present

Community Builder

- Education and training in blockchain development.
- Demonstrate new services and features.
- Conducting workshops, and providing guidance to individuals interested in blockchain technology.

Sdacademy. — Estonia (Remote)

July 2021 - April 2022

JavaScript Tutor

- Leveraged video calls, online chats and email to tutor students remotely.
- Coordinated lesson plans, course materials and discussion questions to prepare for the session.
- Suggested learning resources to increase student interest and retention
- Kept and updated confidential files and records on student information and progress
- Build real time projects with JavaScript for excellent teaching guides

GDSC — (Lead)

February 2022 - April 2021

Google Dev Lead

- Organized a series of events, workshops, and hackathons
- Train aspiring developers in google technologies and other leading technology tools

Education

B.Sc. Computer Science 2022

Federal University Makurdi